Jean-Simon Robert Ouimet

UI/UX Designer

613-552-4904 jsrobertouimet@gmail.com github.com/JSRobertOuimet codepen.io/JSRobertOuimet

Passionate visual designer with a strong inclination towards front-end web development. I like to translate business requirements into seamless experiences informed by user research. I love to turn those experiences into elegant interfaces using the latest technologies. I enjoy both working independently or as part of a team where cooperation is the common denominator. My mother tongue is French and I'm proudly bilingual. I'm a former musician who persistently strives to create that pitch-perfect moment that will make a positive change for my audience.

Areas of Expertise

- User interviews, user scenarios, user flows
- Wireframes, mock-ups, prototypes
- User interface and interaction design
- Human Interface Guidelines and Material Design
- Front-end web development for single-page applications
- Visual identities and brand guidelines
- Iteration process using the Agile methodology
- Requirements gathering and scope definition

Software Proficiencies

- Affinity Designer, Balsamiq Wireframes, Figma, Sketch
- Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign)
- Microsoft Office (Azure DevOps, Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Familiar Technologies

- HTML5, CSS3 (Sass), JS (ES6), Markdown
- AngularJS, Bootstrap, Git, Ionic, Node.js, React

Experience

Kivuto Solutions

UI/UX Designer September 2018 – June 2019, Ottawa, Ontario

Front-end Web Developer
June 2017 – August 2018, Ottawa, Ontario

Worked on Texidium, a multilingual e-reader consumer application

Conducted a UI inventory across five clients using atomic design principles. Worked in tandem with developers to modernized the UI of the application. Designed and implemented new features. Enhanced existing features based on user feedback. Defined requirements for a read aloud feature using user scenarios.

Worked on ELMS, a multilingual enterprise-level application (50 million users)

Ran user interviews to understand usage, pain points, and define personas. Created interactive prototypes to illustrate simplified user flows. Presented findings of user research and recommendations to senior management and project stakeholders. Designed functionality to collect, display and manage payment methods and addresses to support a new subscription-based billing model. Created and maintained a pattern library to accelerate design and development process while facilitating communication with stakeholders and QA testers.

Symbiosys

Front-end Web Developer
June 2016 – September 2016, Montréal, Québec

Implemented user interfaces from provided mock-ups for three hybrid applications: an investment management app, a video chat app based on mutual interests, and an online classified advertising app.

Creative Spectrums

Graphic Designer, Web Designer & Developer January 2013 – Present, Montréal, Québec / Ottawa, Ontario

Gather requirements and define project scope within timeline and budget. Build profitable long-term relationships by providing excellent customer service. Create

visual identities and brand guidelines for a variety of industries. Trace existing bitmap logos to vector graphics. Design administrative documents and marketing material for print and web. Design, develop and maintain websites.

Education

Collège Salette

Attestation of College Studies (ACS), Graphic Design 2013 – 2014, Montréal, Québec

Université de Montréal

Master of Arts (MA), Music, Musicology 2010 – 2012, Montréal, Québec

Université de Montréal

Bachelor of Music (BMus), Musicology 2007 – 2010, Montréal, Québec